

# Taeyoung Kim

ROBOTICS · PERCEPTION ENGINEER

340, Mokdongseo-ro, Yangcheon-gu, Seoul, 08089, Republic of Korea

□ (+82) 10-9686-8177 | **■** tyoung96@yonsei.ac.kr | **☆** taeyoung96.github.io | **回** Taeyoung96

"Nothing ventured, nothing gained."

## Summary.

This is Taeyoung Kim, who wants to become an autonomous driving or robotics Perception engineer. My research interests are Computer Vision and SLAM. I like to take on challenging tasks and I like to grow up with my colleagues around me. That's why I record and share what I did on my Github or Technical Blog. I'm also interested in contributing open-source projects.

## Research Interests

**Computer Vision** Object Detection, Segmentation, Depth Estimation, 3D reconstruction

**SLAM** Visual SLAM, Visual Odometry, Visual Inertial SLAM

## Education \_\_\_\_\_

#### Yonsei University @CILAB

Seoul, S.Korea

Seoul, S.Korea

Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2022

M.S. IN VEHICLE CONVERGENCE ENGINEERING (ADVISOR: PROF. EUNTAI KIM)

Mar. 2022 - Feb. 2024 (Expected)

- · Join the mobile robot team
- Research on visual inertial slam and a study that combines visual slam with deep learning

Kwang Woon University

B.S. IN SCHOOL OF ROBOTICS

• Total GPA: 4.10 / 4.50, Major GPA: 4.41 / 4.50

• Club: BARAM (Robotics Academic Group) - [2020 Staff] , DAISY (English Conversation Club) - [2019 Spring President]

# Work Experience \_\_\_

#### **Computer Vision Lab @Korea Univ**

Seoul, S.Korea

Undergraduate Lab Intern (Advisor: Prof. Sangpil Kim)

Mar. 2021 - Jul. 2021

- Research on Computer Vision using an Event camera
- Event data processing using ESIM

### KIST(Korea Institute of Science and Technology)

Seoul, S.Korea

STUDENT INTERN (ADVISOR: Dr. KANGGEON KIM)

Sep. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Research on Monocular Depth Estimation
- Participated in KIST disinfect robot (AI Disinfection Robot) project [Video]

#### Image Process System Lab @Kwang Woon Univ

Seoul, S.Korea

May. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- Undergraduate Lab Intern (Advisor: Prof. Donggyu Sim)
   Research on Image Processing based on Deep learning
- Participated in seminars related to Deep Learning and Image Processing

## **Publication**

2021.7

#### INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL

### "Standard for the Quantification of a Sterilization Effect Using an Artificial Intelligence Disinfection

2021.11 **Robot"**, Heeju Hong, Wonkook Shin, Jieun Oh, Sunwoo Lee, <u>Taeyoung Kim</u>, Woosub Lee, Jongsuk Choi, Seungbeum Suh and Kanggeon Kim, Sensors 21, no. 23: 7776. https://doi.org/10.3390/s21237776

Sensors

### INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE

"Dense Monocular SLAM applied Depth Estimation",

UR 2021

Taeyoung Kim, Omer Faruk Ince, JongBeom Baek, Jun-Sik Kim, KangGeon Kim, - [Paper], [Video]

(Work in progress)

"Recognition of disinfection targets and generation of semantic map for disinfection robot",

TaeHwan Kim, Taeyoung Kim, GiJae Lee, KangGeon Kim, - [Paper]

KROS 2021

## Honors & Awards

#### AWARDS

2021.5

2020.11	<b>Dean's List</b> , for Academic Excellence	KwangWoon Univ.
2020.9	<b>5th Place on B-track</b> , Korea Health Datathon 2020	NAVER CLOUD
		PLATFORM
2019.10	Dean's List, for Academic Excellence	KwangWoon Univ.

#### Honors

2021-2	National Science and Engineering Undergraudate Scholarship ,	Korea Student Aid
2021-1	for the students, those who have been recommended by the university (Full tuition Scholarship)	Foundation
2020-2	National Science and Engineering Undergraudate Scholarship ,	Korea Student Aid
2020-1	for the students, those who have been recommended by the university (Full tuition Scholarship)	Foundation
2019-2	Full tuition Scholarship, for Top seat last semester	KwangWoon Univ.

## Skills

**Programming** C++/C, Python, JAVA, Matlab **Framework** Pytorch, Tensorflow, Keras **DevOps** Git, Docker, ROS2 / ROS Languages Korean, English

# Extracurricular Activity \_\_\_\_\_

**Technical Blogs** 

WRITERS May. 2020 - Present

• You can easily access the blog using [this link].

- Writing some posts about lecture summary, paper review, some tips for developments.
- To share what I have studied with others and to remember it longer.

## 2021 Open Source Contribution Academy

Aug. 2021 - Nov. 2021 MENTEE

- · I am in the process of translating a Pytorch tutorial into Korean that I want to contribute to the spread of PyTorch.
- Using Github, I developed the ability to collaborate and contribute to open source.
- The open source repository I've contributed can be found [here].

**CLOVA AI RUSH 2021** NAVER AI Lab, NAVER CLOVA

• Only 150 students are allowed to participate in this project.

- I developed my own deep learning model related to multi-label classification.
- I ranked 30th on Project 1-3.

PARTICIPANT

#### **2021 Spring Capstone Design**

KwangWoon Univ.

May. 2021 - Jun.2021

Ministry of Science and ICT

Mar. 2021 - Jun.2021 **PROJECT** 

- I made a wireless charging electric vehicle charging robot.
- I designed the control input algorithm, trained deep learning model, and developed the ROS package.
- The source code related to this project is on my [Github repository].

## **Monocular Depth Estimation with ORB-SLAM2**

BARAM (Robotics Academic Group)

PERSONAL TOY PROJECT Sep. 2020 - Nov. 2020

- I was curious about the performance of the recent depth estimation model.
- Tused 'Monocular Depth Estimation with Transfer Learning pretrained MobileNetV2' model and applied to ORB-SLAM2 also compared with ORB-SLAM2(Monocular mode), ORB-SLAM2(RGB-D mode)
- The source code related to this toy project is on my [Github repository].

TAEYOUNG KIM · CURRICULUM VITAE FEBRUARY 18, 2022

## **Runner Alarm System based on Deep Learning**

BARAM (Robotics Academic Group)

PERSONAL TOY PROJECT Apr. 2020 - Jun. 2020

- I wanted to distinguish between walking children and running children with an object detection model.
- When children are running for an amount of time, a beep sounds.
  The source code related to this toy project is on my [Github repository].